# MD ISLAM

💌 md.islam007@rutgers.edu 🚱 mdislam.com 📞 (347) 459 5013 🕻 mdnahian

SUMMARY

Student at Rutgers University studying Computer Science interested in web development, mobile development, and machine learning. Currently have over 3 years of experience in building cross platform applications for clients and have published 8 applications in the Google Play Store.

**EDUCATION** 

**Rutgers University** 

EMPLOYMENT

B.A. Computer Science (Minor: Mathematics) 2018

Paradox Process, Software Developer Intern, New York, New York

Apr 2017 - Jun 2017

- · Created an iOS and Android application to help people register and track user impulses and emotions
- · Designed user interface using Sketch and developed using React Native and D3.js
- · Aided in testing, debugging, and publishing to the iTunes App Store and Google Play Store

Rutgers University, Web Developer, GS-LSAMP, Newark, NJ

Sep 2015 - May 2016

- . Lead a team to develop and redesign the GS-LSAMP website
- . Created an RSVP feature and an online timesheet with email confirmation using SendGrid API
- Developed website backend using PHP and created a CMS to upload new slides and update content regularly

FBD Distributors Inc., Desktop Support Technician, Maspeth, New York

Aug 2014 - May 2015

- Provided daily technical support and designed, developed, and maintained company website
- · Installed new software per requirements and setup computers for individual staff use
- · Liaised with vendors and purchased supplies

**SKILLS** 

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: Java, PHP, JavaScript, Python, MATLAB, C++WEB TECHNOLOGIES: Flask, Django, Express, Meteor, Laravel, Codelgniter

DATABASES: MySQL, MongoDB, MS SQL

OS/PLATFORMS: Windows Server & Workstation, Linux, Unix

**PROJECTS** 

# Šą̃ ¢

- Ö^ç^|[]^åÁC@[{ ^Æ¢¢'}•ā[}ÁæjåÁÖ|^&d[}Áæ^•\d[]Áæj]|ä&æaā[}Ás@æxÁæ|[¸•Á•^¦•Ád[Áræb}ÁæÁ
  }^,Áæj\*\*æ\*^Áò•óåñÁ;ææ&@j\*Á¤^o\dic
- OB&^] c^å Á § (f ÁOE; \* ^ | Pæ&\ @ ÁFOË; ^ ^ \ Áæ&&^ | ^ | æ (f LÁ); [\* | æ (f LÁ); | \* | æ

## Phishly

- Platform that allows companies to test and train their employees to detect and prevent social engineering attacks
- Developed website back-end and REST API using Python Flask and MongoDB
- · Developed social engineering bot that generates new and deceptive phishing emails

#### ScreenGif

- · Developed Android application to record and share phone screen as a GIF
- Created editing tool to crop recorded GIFs
- Application installed by 165 users in less than 10 days

# **AWARDS**

#### 1st Place, CUNY Hack

- · Web application using NLP that generates notes by aggregating all notes in the classroom
- Using IBM Watson Alchemy API to retrieve text context and subject
- · Using Google Drive API to store and retrieve notes

## 2nd Place, HackNJIT

- · Android app using computer vision and NLP to help people take the right medication
- Using OpenCV to detect words in a photo and generate a black and white image which is fed into Microsoft Cognitive Services OCR
- . Using NLTK to extract the name, description, and usage information from text

### 3rd Place, HackNY

- Android app that allows users to buy and sell mobile hotspot data through tethering
- · Initial connection done using peer-to-peer to transfer funds through PayPal API and encrypted password
- Created REST API using Flask and MongoDB

## New York Tech Meetup, Presentor

• Presented Android app, Peer Wifi, to a theater packed with local technologists

**ACTIVITIES**